Mahendra Indukuri

ABOUT ME

I am a digital product designer and cognitive science student with interests in new product development and entrepreneurship. I have over a year of experience working with technology companies in UI/UX design roles and I have expertise in developing interactive prototypes and style sheets using various tools like **Sketch**, **Adobe XD**, **Adobe CC and Zeplin**. My background and aptitude in design, engineering and psychology help me tackle diverse problems in the domain of user experience and product design.

EDUCATION

University College Dublin - MSc. Cognitive Science

SEPTEMBER 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2020, DUBLIN.

Currently pursuing a master's degree in Cognitive Science focusing in psychology, philosophy of mind, computational modelling, neuropsychology and other contemporary approaches to cognitive science. Course work includes substantial first-hand research and literature research. Working on a thesis project in the domain of Human-Computer Interaction and skill learning.

Indian Institute of Technology Guwahati — Bachelor of Design

JULY 2014 - MAY 2018, GUWAHATI.

Graduated from IIT Guwahati with a bachelor's degree in Design focusing on new media and interaction design. Coursework included project-based courses in graphic design, ergonomics, product design, interaction design and usability engineering.

EXPERIENCE

Silverlabs India (rizzle.tv), Hyderabad — UI/UX Designer

FEBRUARY 2019 - JULY 2019

Worked on Rumbl (currently renamed Rizzle) application, Rumbl is a vlogging and social video creation application. It was conceived, designed and developed from scratch during my tenure at the organisation. Android and iOS applications are live. (visit: rizzle.tv)

- Created user personas and analysed competing apps to find a market gap for a new photo/video mobile app.
- Conducted user interviews and created multiple iterations for A/B testing based on stakeholder feedback.
- Built wireframes, information architecture and task flow for multiple initial versions of the app.
- Created UI mockups including Iconography using Sketch/Adobe XD for both iOS and Android apps.
- Collaborated with UI devs to create micro-interactions, video player interactivity and animations in the app.
- Created Zeplin and additional documentation for UI devs regarding colour codes, aspect ratio, styling, resolutions.

WitCurve Tech., Hyderabad - Product Designer

JULY 2018 - JANUARY 2019

WitCurve's products include web application that functions as an information management tool for K-12 educational institutions and a mobile application for parents for viewing performance-related data and interacting with teachers. (visit: witcurve.com)

- Translated research findings into wireframes and presented multiple iterations low-fidelity mockups to stakeholders.
- Designed the UI/UX for Ionic 3 (hybrid iOS and Android app) based mobile application from scratch, deliverables included high fidelity mockups, style guides using Zeplin, Iconography and Information Architecture of the app.
- Designed UI for a web-based ERP tool based on Angular material framework, deliverables included iconography, high fidelity mockups, information architecture, documentation and animations for various micro-interactions.
- Developed front-end (HTML/CSS/AngularJS) for UI intensive data visualisation features.

Societe Generale Global Solutions Center, Bangalore — Summer Internship (UI/UX Design)

MAY 2017 - JULY 2017

- Designed a web-based application for viewing & editing FPML (Financial Product Markup Language).
- Designed and developed multiple data tables using Angular & Semantic-UI frameworks.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Storytelling in Virtual Reality - Media Lab, Indian Institute of Technology Guwahati

August 2017 - May 2018

Worked on Virtual Reality (VR) and the future of storytelling in VR, explored concepts such as hypermontage and gaze-based interactivity through an interactive prototype for google cardboard developed using unity.

Understanding Motor Chinking — School of Computer Science, University College Dublin

February 2020 - Ongoing

Currently working on my master's thesis project that studies motor chunking in the context of human-computer interaction.